An interface is like a facade or an outline of some imaginary class.
“接口”就像是某假想类的外立面或者轮廓
Its sole purpose is to be inherited by some other class.
其的唯一目的就是被其它类继承
It only defines what needs to be done,
它只定义需要做什么
but not how to do it.
而不是如何去做
In other words, the interface would list the methods that need to be
也就是说 接口会列出类中需要包含的方法
included in the class but no implementation code whatsoever.
但不包括实现代码等
The implementation of these methods are
这些方法的具体实现
the responsibility of the classes implementing that interface.
是由应用了这个接口的类去负责的
Once you implement that interface in a class,
一旦你在一个类中实现了该接口
you can then start instantiating objects as usual.
你就可以像往常一样开始实例化对象
The reason Java introduced interfaces is because of the multiple inheritance problem.
Java 引入接口就是为了解决多重继承的问题
A single class can be extended by multiple classes.
一个类可以被多个类扩展
But a child class is not allowed to extend more than one parent class.
但是一个子类仅允许扩展一个父类
Interfaces, however, don't have that restriction,
但接口却不受此限制
which means that a single class can implement multiple interfaces allowing
这就意味着 一个类可以实现多个接口
for a more flexible design but without the ambiguity problem of the multiple inheritance.
从而使得设计更加灵活 同时也消除了多重继承的歧义问题
Let's have a look at an example.
我们来看一个例子
Imagine you're responsible of implementing a class called Caravan.
想象一下 你要负责实现一个叫做 Caravan 的类
We know that a caravan is half vehicle, half house.
我们知道 caravan 是半车半房的旅行拖车
But if you had a class for a vehicle and a class for a house,
那如果你有一个类是车 一个类是房
we know that you're not allowed to extend both classes at the same time.
却也知道不能同时扩展两个类
A good solution would be to introduce interfaces.
这时 引入接口就是一个好的解决方案
A good interface would be the movable interface, for example,
比如 可移动类接口就是个不错的接口
which would define the methods that any class that moves should include,
它将对任何可移动的类 (比如“车”类)
like the vehicle class, for example.
所应该包含的方法进行定义
Another good interface would be called the habitable interface,
另一个接口叫做可居住的接口
which would also define all the methods that are to be included for any habitable class.
它会对所有可居住类所包含的所有方法进行定义
Once we define those two interfaces,
一旦我们定义了这两个接口
we could then implement both of them in the Caravan class at the same time.
就可以在 Caravan 类中同时实现这两者
Let's have a look at the Java code for that.
我们来看下对应的 Java 代码
Creating an interface in Java is very similar to creating a class.
在 Java 中创建接口的方法与创建类非常相似
Simply swap the keyword class with interface.
只需将关键词 class 替换为 interface 即可
Inside the interface, as you can see,
在接口内 你可以看到
we have listed the method signatures but without
我们列出了方法签名
any implementation code because that's
但没有列出任何实现代码
the responsibility of the class that will be implementing that interface.
因为后者是由实现接口的类负责完成的
The same for the habitable interface,
可居住接口也是一样
which in our case here only includes the canFit method.
本例中的可居住接口仅包括 canFit 方法
Once we create both of those interfaces,
创建好这两个接口
we can then start implementing our Caravan class,
我们就可以开始实现 Caravan 类了
which implements both the habitable and movable interfaces.
它会实现可居住和可移动这两个接口
Notice that I've used the keyword, implements,
请注意 这里我所使用的关键词是 implements
here compared to the keyword, extends.
而非由父类继承子类时
When inheriting from classes,
所用的关键词 extends
implements is the keyword to use when inheriting from interfaces.
implements 是从接口继承时所使用的关键词
Once we implement those interfaces,
在实现了这些接口之后
we have to implement the code for
我们必须执行这两个接口所包含的
every single method included in both those interfaces like
每个方法的代码
the move method which was included in the moveable interface
如可移动接口所包含的移动方法
and the canFit method which was included in the habitable interface.
和可居住接口所包含的 canFit 方法
If there's any method in any of
如果任一接口中的任何方法
those interfaces that was not implemented in the Caravan class,
未在 Caravan 类中实现
that will show a compilation error.
将会显示编译错误
Notice that inheriting interfaces hasn't really saved us
请注意 继承接口并没有像之前我们扩展类时一样
from rewriting any code like we've done before with extended classes.
为我们省去了重写代码的麻烦
That's because interfaces isn't there to help
这是因为接口的意义更多地还是在于
us reduce code as much as enforce a good design.
执行一个好的设计 而非帮我们减少代码
Creating interfaces forces any class that will
创建接口的做法会迫使任何将要实现该接口的类
implement it to have to implement a certain number of methods.
先实现一定数量的方法
This means that later on,
这就意味着
if you have a look at any class that implements
如果将来你看到某个类在实现某接口
a certain interface without looking at the code of that class,
即便不看那个类的代码
you can guarantee that it will include all these methods that are in that interface.
也可以确信 该类已经包含有接口内的所有方法了
So, to summarize everything so far,
让我们来做个总结
we know that interfaces define what a class should do,
我们知道接口定义了类要做什么
but not how to do it.
而不是怎样做
We've seen that creating an interface is very similar to creating a class,
我们也看到创建一个接口和创建一个类非常相似
and we know that the interface's sole purpose
也了解了接口唯一的目的就是
is to be implemented by one or more classes.
被一个或多个类实现
That is, you're not allowed to create
也就是说 你不可以直接从接口
an instance or an object from an interface directly.
创建一个实例或对象
You have to first implement it through a class,
你必须首先通过类来实现它
and then you can create objects from that.
然后才可以从中创建对象
And we've seen that it's not about reducing code or partition.
我们也知道 实现接口并不意味着要减少代码或者分割
It's more about enforcing a good design.
它更关注的是执行一个好的设计